The adventures of an ordinary man at war with the everyday world.
Falling Down is a crime, drama, thriller film directed by Joel Schumacher.
An ordinary man frustrated with the various flaws he sees in society
begins to psychotically and violently lash out against them.
D-Fens, played by Michael Douglas.
Prendergast, played by Robert Duvall.
Beth, played by Barbara Hershey.
Sandra, played by Rachel Ticotin.
Mrs. Prendergast, played by Tuesday Weld.
Surplus Store Owner, played by Frederic Forrest.
Falling Down is a 1993 American action drama film directed by Joel Schumacher,
written by Ebbe Roe Smith, and starring Michael Douglas and Robert Duvall.
Set in Los Angeles, the film tells the story of William Foster, a disgruntled, unemployed defense worker who abandons his car in
the middle of a traffic jam and goes on a violent rampage trying to reach his family for his daughter's birthday.
Martin Prendergast, a retiring police officer, attempts to catch Foster.
On its release, the film received mixed reviews, with some praising the performances
from Douglas and Duvall, while criticizing the film's violence and tone.
It grossed $96 million against a $25 million budget, taking the top spot at
the United States box office in its first two weeks of release.
In later years, the film has gained cult status, with many citing it as one of
Schumacher's best films, as well as one of Douglas's best roles.
The film has since continued to be analyzed for its themes of the
class system, economic pressures, and mental health.
The film explores themes of detective, rocket launcher, fast
food restaurant, retirement, traffic jam.
The tone is emotional and dark and thought_provoking.